in the pocket on third and long. Rush
sack by Chris Jones. Stone cold. It's
caught by Kelsey inside the 10. Inside
the five. Kelsey leaps. Touchdown.
KAREEM HUNT AT [music] THE 10. ANGLING
to the FIVE INTO THE END ZONE. LEFT SIDE
AND IT is good. Good. Here comes a rush
and he's GOING TO GO DOWN. GEORGE
CARLOS.
[music]
WELL, in this Chiefs rewind, Nashville,
Tennessee, the Chiefs lose 26 to9 to the
Tennessee Titans. Chiefs fall to 6 and9
on the season. Uh, this was a game where
I mean, you can't make it up. Gardenner
Mchu, the backup, playing for Patrick
Mahomes, goes down with an injury and
Chris Oloken has to play the most
extended of his career by far. Uh, and
Chris had his moments, but the Chiefs
lose this one.
>> Yeah, tough one for the Chiefs here. Uh,
injuries obviously played a big role in
the result today, but unfortunately I
think we saw some of the same kind of
indicators we've seen all season,
especially in our losses. Think about
third down on both sides of the ball.
Uh, so we're just 1 for nine offensively
on third down in this game. Meanwhile,
Tennessee goes 9 for6 on third down and
10 penalties for the Chiefs here in this
game. Uh, it's our fifth game this year
with double digit penalties. No
coincidence we've lost all five of those
games.
>> Yeah. And the third downs uh when you
look at big plays, the Titans who've
played decent football, they've been
playing their best football the last
three weeks, but a third and four pass
for 25. Third and 10 pass for 24. Third
and six, pass for 15. The game was in
doubt when those third downs uh were
made for big plays and the Chiefs
defense was hanging in there in the
first half, but man, trying to get off
the field on third down has been
something we talk about almost every
week.
>> Yeah, it's tough. I mean, I think our
front seven actually played pretty well
at times in this game. Nick Bolton had a
big play. George Carlos had a sack in
this game. Chris Jones, I think, played
with great energy and heart in this game
despite the circumstances. He stuffs Cam
Ward on that short fourth down attempt.
the quarterback sneak. Uh, but when you
allow that many third down conversions
and especially big plays on long third
downs, that's just backbreaking and we
couldn't overcome it.
>> And Isaiah Pacheco 75 yds all purpose in
this game. It was his best game since
the Raiders game and the Chiefs actually
put some things together. A drive at the
end of the second quarter with Chris
Odoken who had not completed a pass in
his career uh in this until this game.
Uh, and so there were some things to try
to extract out of it, getting ready for
a short week, but it was good to see PCO
get positive plays.
>> Yeah. And Chris Oloken, I'm happy for
him. Uh, he's been grinding on the
practice squad for four years. Been here
a long time. Hasn't played a whole lot.
Got in the week 18 game last year, but
didn't complete a pass. He goes 11 for
16 today for 111 yards. Brought some
juice and some energy to a game that
otherwise was kind of lacking it, I
[laughter] think. Uh, he goes five for
five for 40 yards on the drive you were
talking about at the end of the first
half. also moved the ball after the
fourth down went our way and we got the
ball with a short field in the third
quarter. Uh moved the ball with some
great throws and got us a field goal.
But again, just not enough in the end
when you have that many penalties and
those struggles on both sides of the
ball on third down.
>> Saw some guys worry up. You mentioned
Bolton 10 plus tackles for the 22nd
time. That's second in Chief's history
only behind Derek Johnson. And then
before we go to the podium, a mention
here of Travis Kelce. He now with 800
yards receiving has done it 12 straight
years. Only he and Jerry Rice have done
it in the history of the National
Football League. Let that one soak in
for a bit. But now let's go to the
podium and hear from Coach Reed.
[clears throat]
All right. Um as far as the injuries go,
uh Gardner [clears throat] hurt his left
knee. Um we don't have any results for
you here. we'll we'll get that when he
has a chance to have an MRI on it. So,
um as far as uh things go, I appreciate
the effort of the guys. We got a lot of
guys that are having an opportunity here
to play and um it's not as smooth as you
wanted obviously. Uh we've had penalties
um all over the place. So, that uh
that's not helping us get off the field
or stay on the field. And uh we've got
to clean clean that up. Um, but the
positive you can take out of this is an
opportunity for guys to play and then
obviously we have a short week here and
we need to get ourselves back and and
going for for a good Denver team. So
that time's yours.
>> Andy, you said you appreciate the
effort. How would you characterize the
energy overall? I'm sure it was hard to
have guys ready for this with all the
things going on.
>> Yeah, so I Yeah, the guys I thought were
were good. I didn't think that was an
issue. Um they, you know, they came out,
they played hard and did their did their
thing. We were just short on a few spots
there. So um and that that got us along
with the penalties. But as far as the
the other part goes, they were I
appreciate the Chris's and the uh
Bolton's and Kelsey's and Cre, you know,
Trey for pushing through and playing. I
mean, um, [clears throat] those are guys
that very easily, uh, could take take a
day off, but I appreciate the [laughter]
effort they put in.
>> And you always you're missing guys every
game. It's the nature of the league.
What ways do you have presence besides
just, you know, his onfield play leading
up to the game provide a lot of energy
obviously?
>> Yeah, I I surely don't want to take
anything away from that. Um, because he
he does bring great energy. um you
expect other people to step up and go
and uh I thought I saw that this week
with guys trying to step in and and
raising it up a little bit. Um it wasn't
[clears throat] wasn't uh good enough
but uh going forward. So we just you got
to have to eliminate these mistakes, you
know, that's the the biggest thing in a
game like this.
>> Did Chris's performance kind of reps?
>> Yeah, I listen I thought [laughter] he
did I thought he did okay. He he was
able to get us moving a little bit and
um you know I probably could give him
better stuff to to work with but uh in
particular get him some more reps during
the week he he didn't didn't have any
reps to to lead him but I thought for
what he was asked to do I thought he did
a nice job.
>> Could you uh see what happened on the on
the safety there like some line didn't
know if it was a run or pass. What was
your
>> Yeah. I I don't I can't answer that.
Yeah. I thought they knew what they were
doing. Yeah,
>> with u
you know you said that obviously with
you are playing guys but like you guys
didn't play Rashard yesterday or the
Royals or Jeffrey B just what goes into
the decision to play in experience maybe
young guy versus not playing
>> yeah we got him a few reps in there you
know so 24 had a package and
[clears throat] so did
um you know the well they all did they
all had a little bit uh of a package
[clears throat] in there but the other
guys want to play too as they And so you
give, you know, they want to go
[clears throat] win the game and so
that's what you do. You try to try to
come out on the top end of it. But we
did have packages for Royals and two for
fourth or something.
>> Where is Jaylen right now just in his
progression as you said 16
the course of the season?
>> Yeah. Uh, you know, he went through the
injury part of it. [clears throat] He
came back and uh I felt like the last
couple weeks he's been doing doing
better. uh this week we gave him a
little bit more uh during the week to to
work with. So um but he's going to be
okay down the road here.
>> Andy, uh six and nine, this will be your
first losing season here in Kansas City.
Just what does it tell you about the
sustainability that you have had prior
to the season and just your just initial
reactions on how this season's gone so
far?
>> Yeah, nobody likes to lose in this
business. So, um, uh, but my hat goes
off for the guys that have put together
all these these years. Um, that's that's
part of it. Uh, we can learn from it and
need to do that going forward. So, it's,
uh, sometimes a good kick in the tail
helps you there, you know, coaches and
[clears throat] and players. So,
>> you mentioned the shortness. How
difficult will it be to prepare Chris?
Yeah, just by numbers if that's the case
and uh Brett's on it and looking at
different people there. Yeah. Sam, I
don't know you saw it seemed like Trey
and Creed were trying to light a fire
under some teammates after that save.
Just wonder what you've seen from them.
Obviously, that is maybe one situation
where Patrick not being here just see
some other guys sort of ste.
>> Yeah, I thought they did a good job with
that. Um, [clears throat]
you know, we had a mistake there that
needed corrected and they got to it
before the coaches got to it. So, before
we get them off the field, but that's uh
that's all part of it.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thanks, coach.
>> Yep.
>> Um, that's always disappointing when you
lose, man. Um, I played this game since
a young kid. All I wanted to do was have
fun and win. And anytime I'm able to
step on the field, that's the goal. Have
fun most importantly and I always try to
finish with a dove. And today we was a
little unfortunate, but um
[clears throat] we preached on giving
high effort. I think a lot of guys flew
around, a lot of guys got new
opportunities and um we're going to keep
it going. We got two more opportunities
left at the end of the season and we're
going to try to finish strong.
[cough]
>> Chris, [clears throat] a fairly
unprecedented situation where you lost a
starting quarterback in two consecutive
games on the sideline. Did you feel any
extra pressure as a defense when you
found out?
>> I mean, it's always unfortunate to to
just lose a player, better yet, we're
talking about a quarterback who u
facilitates the ball on our team. It's
so, you know, um definitely an
unprecedented situation that I never
been a part of. But, you know, um as
coach Ree say, we just u we work with
who we got and we just keep it moving.
Um, defense, we always have the pressure
on us to stop, give our ball, I mean,
offense the ball in good field situation
and get off the field on third, third
down. So, you know, today it was no
different. You
>> said you never been in a situation like
this before. How important is it you a
leader on this team to rally around a
practice squad quarterback that's got to
come in and lead your team for the
majority of the game?
>> I think my job don't change on this
team. I'm I'm still who I am. Um, no
matter the record, if we were 0 and6,
I'm still who I am. I still play the
game with passion. I still love what I
do. Um, I'm still going out there fired
up every play, every opportunity I'm on
the field and everybody else on defense.
Um, it's not our job to predict the
situation. We're in a very unfortunate
situation where sometimes you can't
control it and it's okay. Um, you know,
you can finish strong. You can worry
about the things you can control, which
is your attitude and your effort. You
know, a lot of people can talk when
they're up. It's about those that that
has character when you're down or you're
not in a favorable position.
>> How much do you feel so today?
>> I mean, we're talking about starters on
our defense. Very important pieces on
our defense. We're talking about a
corner who has made all pro in the last
two to three years. We're talking about
Leo Chanel who we can move around. I
mean that presence definitely was missed
but also gave us opportunity to look at
younger guys who who has the opportunity
[snorts] to play today. You know
probably didn't have the opportunity
when they was there. So you know it's a
building point something we can build
off of especially with the younger guys
going into this Thursday.
>> You're largely like a positive guy
positive presence. What tells you that
maybe this season's more of a blond
not only the two games next year?
[clears throat]
>> Well we look at it. This team is a
makeup of last year team and last year
team went what 14-2 15-2 something like
that and there's not many pieces missing
and then you look at what's the
difference the difference this year is
one score games we didn't finish as
Chris we it was we previously did and
that can make a difference cuz this
league the margin for error is so small
and we have so many games which are one
score games whether it was the offense
defense or merely just special teams. We
got to uh [clears throat] we got to hone
in on finishing finishing finishing
especially at the end of the game.
>> Chris, what are your thoughts on count
more looking forward? [clears throat]
>> He played well today. We sent a lot of
blitzes at him. He was able to get out,
use his legs and um get the ball out of
his hands. Um you know um and they ran
the ball really really well against us
today. I think he had 22 21 carries for
98 yards. You know, um when they're able
to run the ball as successful, then it
opens up thing for the offense. And we
didn't do a really good job of stopping
the run as we did in the previous week.
So, we can hone in on that. Coming up
with Denver Brook's uh division
[clears throat] opponent, it's going to
be tough. They like to run the ball.
They like to play physical. So, this
week going in the film, we got to up our
physicality.
>> Last one. Anybody? Thanks, Chris.
>> Thank you, guys.
>> Thank you.
Yeah, you know, um first off, you know,
praying for, you know, not only Pat and
what happened last week, but also
Gardner. Um we don't know the severity
of the injury yet, but uh you know, our
our QB room is so close. And so, uh when
you see, you know, good friends go down
like that, um you know, it's really
tough. And then for me, you know, been
being here for four years, you know,
I've always, you know, you always walk
through when your first moment's going
to be and you know, when you're going to
sort of get an opportunity. And so, uh,
I've really just attacked these last
four years like, you know, you never
know. And, um, today just happened to
be, you know, an opportunity for me and,
uh, I wanted to take full advantage of
it.
>> Players always say, you know, backup
player always say stay ready. That's our
job is to stay ready. I would imagine
this is a great why you do that.
>> Yeah, 100%. You know, you like I just
said, you you never know when your
number's going to be called. Um, whether
it's a freak injury or, you know, you
just never know when you're going to go
in. So, uh, we do a really good job of
making sure everyone's prepared and, uh,
you know, being with Pat and seeing him
go through his routine, you know, the
last four years. And Gardner, he's been
awesome in the room and really helping
me, you know, come along and develop as
well. So, um, you know, all the credit
to those guys and our coaching staff.
Uh, they made it pretty easy for me out
there today.
>> How you prepare yourself?
Uh, I mean, obviously you see Gardner go
down and I hate it for him and then the
next thing, you know, my mind went to
is, "All right, well, I got to rally the
troops now and, you know, go win a
football game." Um, you know, those
those guys out there, man, they they
battled their asses off and, uh, I can't
say enough good things about, you know,
you're out there and my first completion
said to Travis Kelce, I mean, you know,
uh, built a great relationship with him
over the last couple years, but if you
would have told me my first, you know,
completion that if I was going to be to
him, probably would have laughed at you.
So, uh, you know, those guys were
awesome. And um you know now we have a
short week and we got to you know move
forward.
>> What did you know about what did you
learn about yourself in this moment?
>> Um that the moment wasn't too big for me
you know um I felt really calm out
there. Felt like uh you know I was
seeing things pretty good. Game didn't
seem too fast for me and um you just
never know how you're going to react in
those situations until you're in it. And
uh you know I'm never never too high,
never too low in those moments. And so
it was good to go out there and get
some, you know, live, you know, regular
season snaps because that's just
something that I haven't really had, you
know, these past four years. So
>> Chris, obviously you guys miss Patrick
on the field, but just his presence
around on on a game day. What do you
miss about that?
>> Uh, I mean, Pat is the first dude. I
mean, he I checked my phone, he was the
first dude that texted me. Um, he's the
first dude to help someone out, lend a
helping hand just, you know, in past
preseason stuff like that, he's always,
you know, in the QB's year, whether it's
me and Gardner, you know, whoever's been
here. Um, everyone misses his presence.
You know, not only me in the QB room,
but the whole team. Uh, you know,
everyone in the building in Kansas City,
you know, we uh we're we we go off 15.
So, uh, you know, he's he's doing his
best right now. He's going to, you know,
he's going to come back, you know, 100%
next year.
>> Yeah. After the game.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Just to confirm, Patrick texted you
right after the game.
>> Yeah. He was I opened my phone. He was
the first text I saw. And, uh, you know,
just that's the type of guy he is. Um,
you know, we've gotten gotten pretty
close for the last four years. and you
know it's someone you know I don't I
don't have a big brother so in a way
he's been you know taking over like a
big brother role for me and uh not only
you know on the field and you know my
development but also off the field and
you know just sort of um just always
being there for me and so he's a great
friend and you know um he's like that
with everyone there's not a bad thing I
could say about him
>> a short week guys how how are you
looking at this challenge of being ready
by Thursday
>> I'm ready for the opportunity it's a
great opportunity it's not only great
opportunity for me but a great
opportunity for our team you you know,
uh, go out there and battle, man. That's
all I can ask of these guys. Go out
there and battle. Obviously, we have a
lot of young guys playing. Um, but it's
great experience, you know, not only for
me, but for all of our young guys
playing. Um, it's going to be real
valuable for us, you know, moving
forward for years to come here in Kansas
City. And, uh, you know, it's Christmas
Day. You know, uh, the the possibility
of me making a first on Christmas Day
is, uh, pretty special. You know, I have
family in town, stuff like that. So, um,
you know, I'm looking forward to it.
from practice squad to
>> pod press conference podium. I mean, are
you able to appreciate or at least
>> be mindful of the moment or is it just
business business for now?
>> Uh, I think you always got to, you know,
appreciate the moment, you know. I think
Trav said earlier in the week, you know,
um, anytime you get to, you know, strap
on the pad and play an NFL game, that's
special and, uh, something I've, you
know, been looking forward to and
wanting to do, you know, since I was,
uh, you know, four years old. So to have
this opportunity, I mean, you you always
watch postgame conferences and, you
know, being here in front of you guys
now. So it's it's surreal, but also, you
know, it's uh it's business as usual,
you know, time to go to work and, you
know, get ready for Denver.
>> Chris, in game, how much are you drawing
from what you've learned from that so
far?
>> Oh, a bunch. You know, just certain
situations and play calls he likes. Uh,
you know, I think the biggest thing is
the energy that he gives to the team.
You know, those guys feeling that
energy. you know, feeling like, you
know, no matter who goes down, you know,
next man up and, you know, it's time to
step up and and play and battle with
your guys. And, you know, I that's when
I first came in that I wanted the guys
to know like, hey, I'm I'm here. We're
going to win this football game. We're
going to go in there. I'm going to give
you everything I got. And I expect the
same from them. And so, um, you know,
that's probably what I learned from him
the most.
>> Your scramble earlier and, you know, you
threw right before.
>> Yeah. No, I think I sort of got because
as soon as I threw, I looked right at
the, you know, line of scrimmage and
I've seen him do that a couple times.
[laughter]
I I sort of had to, you know, make sure
I've just seen it so many times. It's
where I naturally went to. But, uh, you
know, I've learned a lot from him.
>> Chris, right before halftime, you led
the team to points. I can't imagine
you've had a lot of practice reps
running the two-minute drill. When the
last time you've done that?
>> Oh, man. Great question. Uh, probably uh
probably training camp and got a couple
reps at it. But, uh, also I've been here
for two years and I've I've seen enough
reps. I've I know our two-minute calls,
you know, I know what we're looking to
do. Obviously, in that situation, you're
just trying to get points out of it. And
um to be honest, I mean, I feel like
that's when I'm playing my best. You
know, I'm just playing free, no huddle.
Um we're sort of, you know, just on the
ball and just, you know, let me let me
go let me go rip it. So um those those
situations, you know, even coach Jordy,
our quarterback, coach told me he's
like, "Just win your best." So go out
there and do your thing. And I was I was
really happy that we're able to go get
some points right there.
>> Thank you, Chris.
>> Appreciate you guys.
>> Congrats.
>> So at the beginning of the radio
broadcast, I always give the injury
report. It's like I could have had a
week to give it and then now um with
Gardenner Mchu going down, there's some
reports that it's serious, but we'll
wait to see what the chief's medical
staff and athletic training staff says
about Gardner Menchu, but you got a
short week now uh moving forward. And we
talked about the rookies
struggle in this game. He had the ball
starts early. Jeffrey Simmons is
obviously in his head. Uh it was a rough
day for the guys that we had on the
list.
>> Yeah. And not enough though. No touches
for Royals and only one touch I think
for uh Rashard Smith.
>> Yeah, on one end because we had the
struggles on third down, we only ran 43
offensive plays today. Uh I wonder maybe
if we ran more plays and were able to
convert on third down, had some longer
drives, maybe we would have seen more of
those guys at skill position spots, but
didn't work out that way. Overall with
some of these young guys struggling,
this is going to happen uh for any
professional football player. Um, as
excited as we were about Essa in those
first couple of games, we knew he was
going to have some struggles, I think,
for him. Now, how do you respond to
that? How do you rebound? How do you go
out there and put a good football game
together against a very good defensive
front in Denver next week? And that's
the case for all of our young guys that
maybe struggled a little bit today. We
can still use this time as a benefit,
right? What do you learn from this
experience here today? If you can learn
from today, hopefully that can help us
down the road.
>> No. Williams, we talked about him.
Played physical in this game. Gelati had
the hold that he had a lot of good
things uh in this game and then Nolles
had the jump on the fourth and one the
field goal to give him a new time they
could run time off the clock and that's
just a mistake he hasn't made all year
and so
>> evaluating these guys giving him more of
a responsibility this is all valuable
going to 2026.
>> Yeah, I'll give Nolles some credit. Uh I
think in the first half on Tennessee's
first touchdown drive he made a great
play at the goal line to save a
touchdown. Now, Tennessee scored the
very next play, so we're not going to
remember that or talk about it much, but
it was a really nice play by Kevin
Nolles. But then again, yeah, you extend
a drive that eventually ends in points
for Tennessee when they were off the
field with that uh offside penalty. You
can't have that, right? And again,
that's a young player learning. Learn
from these moments. You're going to make
mistakes and of course, we end up losing
this game. Learn from today and don't
waste it.
>> Here's what's crazy. The Chiefs have
hours. Hours. just hours because there's
uh a lot to discuss here with all the
injuries, who's going to fill in. I
mean, you got to have a backup
quarterback. Who's that going to be?
Noah Gray is the emergency guy, but you
had just hours to try to figure out a
game plan and piece something together
to get ready for Denver, and they're
going to they're they're needing that
game in the worst way.
>> Yeah, if Denver wins that game, if they
win today as well, I believe they clinch
the one seat. They're playing to win. Uh
it's going to be tough for the Chiefs,
but this is where you dig deep, right? I
mean, we're missing a lot of our guys
right now, and the season has not gone
the way any of us expected. I mean,
unfortunately, we just clenched today,
our first losing season since 2012. Not
a lot of fun right now, but what do you
learn from this time? How can you be
better immediately because of how today
went? And we're going to learn a lot
about these young guys and our team over
the next few days and how they go out
and play against the Broncos.
>> And you have a Pro Football Hall of Fame
first ballot coach and a Pro Football
Hall of Fame first ballot tight end. you
figure it out and just hours to do it.
Merry Christmas and happy holidays to
you and your family. We'll keep you
updated on the hours that we have prior
to that game. Chiefs lose it here 269 to
Tennessee. Thanks for joining us on this
edition of Chiefs Rewind. Chiefs Rewind
is brought to you by Ford, the official
car and truck of the Kansas City Chiefs,
and by Community America Credit Union,
the official banking partner of the
Kansas City Chiefs.